<resources>
    <string name="app_name">NITER Campuspedia</string>
    <string name="about1">National Institute of Textile Engineering and Research (NITER) is the first education institute running as a Public-Private-Partnership (PPP) organization under the Ministry of Textiles and Jute, GoB. It is located in its own campus at Nayarhat, Savar, Dhaka adjacent to the Dhaka-Aricha highway and enjoys excellent communication facilities connecting among important cities of the country. The total campus area of NITER is 13.06 Acres with adequate built up space in its academic, administrative, hostels, Canteen and other buildings.

As per the decision of the Ministry of Textiles and Jute, NITER has been running under the management of ‘Bangladesh Textile Mills Association (BTMA)’ since September 2008. An operational agreement was signed between ‘Bangladesh Textile Mills Association (BTMA)’ and ‘Bangladesh Textile Mills Corporation (BTMC)’ under the Ministry of Textiles and Jute. After signing the agreement, BTMA actively took the responsibilities of NITER on May, 2009. That time it was known as ‘National Institute of Textile Training Research and Design (NITTRAD)’.

BTMA expanded the academic span of the institute and started B. Sc. in Textile Engineering course under the Faculty of Engineering and Technology of the University of Dhaka. From 2010-2011 session, B. Sc. in Textile Engineering course was started. Considering the nature and future prospect of this institute, the University of Dhaka requested the Ministry of Textiles and Jute to change the name of NITTRAD. Accordingly the Ministry renamed NITTRAD as ‘National Institute of Textile Engineering and Research (NITER)’ from January 2013.</string>
    <string name="about2">Apart from Textile Engineering course, NITER is now offering four other important engineering courses namely B. Sc. in Industrial and Production Engineering (IPE) and Fashion Design and Apparel Engineering (FDAE), Computer Science and Engineering (CSE) and Electrical and Electronics Engineering (EEE) to meet the present demand skilled manpower as well as the automation of our Textile and allied sector. Furthermore NITER has started M.Sc. in Textile Engineering course under the Faculty of Engineering and Technology and MBA in Textile and Apparel Value Chain under the faculty of Business Studies of the University of Dhaka. Near about 2500 students are studying in these courses and the numbers are increasing every year.

NITER is being operated by a ‘Governing Body’ consists of the members from BTMA, Ministry of Textiles and Jute, BTMC, University of Dhaka and from the institute as well. Mohammad Ali Khokon, renowned industrialist and the President of BTMA is the Chairman of the Governing Body.</string>

    <string name="about3">NITER has 13.06 acres of land with vibrant greenery and scenic beauty. NITER has adequate numbers of qualified faculty members, officers, and staff. There are Academic buildings and Administrative building with sufficient space. It has all kinds of modern laboratories, sufficient number of class-rooms with adequate space, web-based library, fully equipped computer labs with internet facilities, separate hostels for male and female students with amenities, canteen, playground and indoor games, wifi-zone campus etc. There are several clubs of student activities functioning in different fields. Many seminars, workshops, events take place under different clubs.

    Furthermore, NITER has a unique wing namely ‘Center for Research and Industrial Relations (CRIR)’ for operating its collaborative research and innovative activities, student’s industrial trainings as well as job placements. Generally a NITER graduate has good demand in the textile job sector and gets employed rapidly.

    There is a Proctorial-body to oversee the rules and regulations and the disciplinary activities of the students. Similarly, Hostels Superintendents are there to look after the resident students of NITER. There are also teacher’s quarters inside the NITER campus.</string>
    <string name="history">In the late 1970s, the public textile mills under the Bangladesh Textile Mills Corporation (BTMC) were operating at a loss.[1] BTMC knew it needed skilled personnel to turn the mills around. To that end, and to serve the mills testing and consulting needs, in 1979 it established a training institute at Savar, the Textile Industry Development Centre (TIDC).For the first five years, the United Nations Development Programme (UNDP), through the United Nations Industrial Development Organization (UNIDO), supported infrastructure, curriculum development, and staff training at TIDC.[1][3]

In 1994 TIDCs name changed to National Institute of Textile Training Research and Design (NITTRAD). Later the Ministry of Textiles and Jute decided to run NITTRAD under public–private partnership (PPP) and handed over its operational management to Bangladesh Textile Mills Association (BTMA) under the Ministry of Textile and Jute. From 1 January 2013, the Ministry of Textiles and Jute, according to a suggestion from the University of Dhaka, changed the name of the institute to National Institute of Textile Engineering and Research. From 2010 to 2011 session NITER started Bachelor of Science in Textile engineering course under the University of Dhaka. It was initiated by the then president of BTMA, Mr. Abdul Hai Sarkar.

It also provides practical and training classes of textile engineering to students of private universities in Bangladesh.</string>

    <string name="admin">The Institutes Administration building is where we run things efficiently, showing we want to do our best. It looks modern and has cool stuff, showing we like new ideas. All the activities of NITER  are controlled by the Administration.</string>

    <string name="ad101">The registration room at the NITER  is where students academic enroll in courses, and access important academic information. Its a vital hub for administrative processes, helping students navigate their academic responsibilities and progress in their engineering studies.</string>
    <string name="BC">The Bangabandhu Corner of NITER is a dedicated space where we honor the life and legacy of Sheikh Mujibur Rahman, also known as Bangabandhu, a prominent leader in the history of Bangladesh. This corner showcases his achievements, some books, speeches, and memorabilia, reminding us of his significant contributions to our nations independence and progress. It serves as a source of inspiration and education, ensuring that his ideals continue to resonate with generations to come.</string>
    <string name="ad103">The registrars office at NITER is the administrative hub for academic records and student information. It manages enrollment, transcripts, and official documentation, ensuring the smooth progression of students through their educational journey. This vital office plays a crucial role in maintaining the integrity of academic records and providing support to students as they navigate their educational paths.</string>
    <string name="ad104">The Office of Accounts and Audits in our Engineering institute is responsible for managing finances, budgets, and auditing. It ensures the responsible use of funds, maintaining transparency and supporting the institutions educational mission. This office plays a vital role in our institutes financial health and sustainability</string>
    <string name="ad102">The account section of NITER takes care of all the money stuff. They handle tuition fees, scholarships, and expenses. Its like the financial headquarters that keeps everything in order for students and the institution.</string>
    <string name="dr">The Directors room in our NITER is the hub of leadership, where important decisions are made and strategic plans are crafted. It embodies the institutes commitment to effective governance and academic excellence, providing a space for key discussions and initiatives.</string>
    <string name="ad108">Our Engineering institutes IT and Maintenance Office is the central point for technological support and facility upkeep. It ensures that our campus remains technologically advanced and well-maintained, creating a conducive learning environment. This office plays a vital role in keeping our institute running smoothly.</string>
    <string name="ad110">The meeting room at our engineering institute is a space where ideas are born, decisions are made, and collaborations thrive. It serves as the heart of productive discussions and strategic planning, fostering innovation and progress within the institution. This room plays a pivotal role in shaping the future of our engineering education.</string>
    <string name="ad111">The Advanced Computer Lab in NITER is a cutting-edge facility designed to empower students with the latest technology and resources. Equipped with high-performance computers and specialized software, it provides an ideal environment for research, programming, and innovation. This lab is a hub for students to develop their technical skills, engage in complex simulations, and stay at the forefront of technological advancements, enhancing their readiness for the engineering challenges of the future.</string>
    <string name="ad202">The conference room in our engineering institute is a well-equipped facility designed to accommodate important gatherings, seminars, and academic discussions. Its spacious layout and audiovisual capabilities make it an ideal venue for sharing knowledge and fostering collaboration. This room plays a pivotal role in facilitating meaningful exchanges of ideas and promoting academic excellence within our institution, enhancing the overall learning experience.</string>
    <string name="ad205">The Examination Controller Office in our engineering institute manages and oversees all aspects of the examination process, ensuring its fairness and integrity. It plays a crucial role in scheduling exams, handling student registrations, and maintaining academic records. This office is dedicated to upholding the highest standards of examination administration to support student success.</string>
    <string name="CR">Classrooms in NITER are equipped with state-of-the-art technology and comfortable seating, providing an ideal environment for effective teaching and learning. They are designed to foster interactive and engaging educational experiences</string>
    <string name="ac105">The Wet Processing Lab at our Institute  is an essential facility where students delve into the intricate world of textile treatments. Here, they learn the art and science of dyeing, printing, and finishing fabrics through hands-on experimentation. This lab equips future textile professionals with practical skills and knowledge, preparing them for the dynamic and innovative textile industry. It serves as a hub for creativity and innovation in textile engineering education.</string>
    <string name="ac106">The Proctor Office, also known as the Hostel Superintendent\'s Office, is a pivotal administrative center within our Engineering institutes hostel facilities. It manages student accommodations, ensures discipline, and provides a supportive environment for residents. This office plays a vital role in fostering a safe and conducive atmosphere for student living.</string>
    <string name="ac107">The garments Washing Lab in our  Institute is a specialized facility where students gain practical experience in the techniques and processes involved in garment washing and finishing. This hands-on learning environment equips future professionals with the skills needed in the textile and fashion industry. It serves as a hub for creativity and innovation in garment design and production.</string>
    <string name="ac108">The Wet Processing Lab in our Engineering Institute is a dedicated facility where students gain hands-on experience in textile treatments like dyeing, printing, and finishing. It provides a practical learning environment for students to understand and apply various wet processing techniques. This lab is integral to preparing our future textile engineers for the dynamic textile industry.</string>
    <string name="ac109">The Chemistry Lab in our NITER is a vital space for students to conduct experiments and explore chemical principles relevant to their engineering studies. Equipped with state-of-the-art instrumentation and safety measures, it fosters a safe and engaging learning environment. This lab plays a critical role in enhancing students\' understanding of chemical processes and their applications in engineering disciplines.</string>
    <string name="ac110">The Electrical Helpdesk and Complaint Room is a dedicated facility for students and staff to seek assistance with electrical issues and report any concerns. It ensures a safe and well-maintained campus environment. This room plays a crucial role in addressing electrical-related needs promptly and efficiently.</string>
    <string name="ac111">The Foundry and Casting Room is a specialized workspace where students gain practical experience in metal casting and molding processes. It provides hands-on training and experimentation opportunities, preparing students for careers in manufacturing and metallurgy. This room is an essential component of our engineering education, fostering skills and knowledge in foundry and casting techniques.</string>
    <string name="ac112">The Fluid Mechanics and Machinery Lab represents a crucial facility for students to study fluid dynamics and the operation of various mechanical systems. It offers hands-on experiments and real-world applications, enhancing students\' understanding of fluid mechanics principles. This lab plays a pivotal role in preparing future engineers with practical skills for industries involving fluid dynamics and machinery.</string>
    <string name="ac113">The Physics Lab in NITER signifies a dynamic space where students engage in hands-on experiments and scientific exploration. Equipped with advanced instrumentation, it fosters an environment for students to apply theoretical concepts to practical phenomena. This lab is instrumental in nurturing critical thinking and problem-solving skills among future engineers</string>
    <string name="ac114">The Manufacturing Process Lab is a state-of-the-art facility where students gain practical experience in various production techniques. It provides hands-on training in machining, casting, and forming processes, preparing students for careers in manufacturing and production engineering. This lab is a cornerstone of our engineering education, fostering essential skills for industries involved in the manufacturing sector.</string>
    <string name="ac115">The mechanical Workshop at our engineering institute signifies a versatile facility equipped for hands-on learning and fabrication. Here, students acquire practical skills in machining, welding, and mechanical systems assembly. This workshop serves as a vital training ground for future mechanical engineers, promoting hands-on problem-solving and innovation.</string>
    <string name="ac117">Weaving Lab is a specialized facility where students gain practical expertise in textile weaving techniques. Equipped with modern looms and equipment, it provides a hands-on environment for mastering the art of fabric creation. This lab is integral to preparing students for careers in the textile and fashion industry by honing their weaving skills and creativity.</string>
    <string name="ac118"> The knitting Lab in our engineering institute represents a dedicated space where students learn and practice various knitting techniques. Equipped with state-of-the-art knitting machines, it offers hands-on experience in fabric production and garment design. This lab plays a pivotal role in nurturing skills for the textile and fashion industry, promoting creativity and innovation among students.</string>
    <string name="ac202">Computer Lab is a high-tech facility equipped with the latest technology and software, providing students with an optimal environment for programming, simulations, and research. It serves as a dynamic hub where students gain hands-on experience in solving complex engineering problems and honing their digital skills. This lab is essential for fostering technological proficiency and innovation among our future engineers.</string>
    <string name="ac202B">The Center for Research and Industrial Relations in NITER serves as a pivotal bridge between academia and industry, fostering collaborations that drive innovation and address real-world engineering challenges. Through research initiatives and partnerships, it empowers students and faculty to work on cutting-edge projects, enhancing their practical knowledge and industry-relevant skills. This center plays a crucial role in promoting a symbiotic relationship between our institution and the engineering industry, contributing to both academic excellence and industrial advancement.</string>
    <string name="ac203"> Product Design and Ergonomics Lab in our engineering institute is a specialized facility where students delve into the creative process of designing user-friendly and efficient products. Equipped with advanced design software and ergonomic equipment, it fosters innovation and user-centric design principles. This lab plays a pivotal role in nurturing the skills and expertise necessary for product designers and engineers to excel in today\'s competitive market.</string>
    <string name="ac205">The Communication and Computer Networks Lab in our institute is a cutting-edge facility that empowers students to explore the intricate world of network technologies and communication systems. Equipped with advanced networking hardware and software, it offers hands-on experience in designing, configuring, and troubleshooting networks. This lab plays a pivotal role in preparing future engineers with practical skills and expertise crucial for the ever-evolving field of communication and computer networks.</string>
    <string name="ac208">The Engineering Drawing Graphic Lab in our NITER is a specialized facility equipped with advanced drafting tools and software for students to master the art of technical drawing and visualization. It provides hands-on experience in creating precise engineering designs and blueprints. This lab is essential for nurturing essential skills in engineering graphics and design, preparing students for the practical aspects of their engineering careers.</string>
    <string name="M">NITEr mosque is situated in the academic building-1 on the top floor beside the Engineering drawing graphic lab.</string>
    <string name="ac124">The Spinning Laboratory in NITER is a specialized facility where students learn the intricacies of textile spinning processes. It provides hands-on experience with spinning machinery and equipment, allowing students to master yarn production techniques. This laboratory is instrumental in preparing students for careers in the textile industry by honing their skills in this essential textile manufacturing step.</string>
    <string name="ac126">The Electrical Circuits/Electronics Lab in our engineering institute is a hands-on facility where students apply theoretical knowledge to practical experiments. Equipped with modern equipment and components, it offers valuable experience in designing and testing electronic circuits. This lab is instrumental in enhancing students\' understanding and skills in electrical engineering, preparing them for real-world applications in electronics and circuit design.</string>
    <string name="ac127">The Materials and Mechanics Lab in NITER is a versatile space where students explore the properties and behavior of various materials under different mechanical conditions. It offers hands-on experiments and testing of materials to understand their strength, durability, and performance. This lab plays a pivotal role in equipping future engineers with the knowledge and skills necessary for materials selection and structural analysis in engineering projects.</string>
    <string name="EEE">The Control System and Instruction Lab for EEE (Electrical and Electronic Engineering) in our engineering institute is a dedicated facility where students focus on designing, analyzing, and implementing control systems specific to electrical and electronic applications. It offers hands-on training with advanced equipment and software, enabling students to work on automation, robotics, and electrical control projects. This lab plays a crucial role in shaping the skills and expertise of EEE students, preparing them for roles in industries that demand precise control and automation solutions.</string>
    <string name="ac128">The Drawing and Draping Lab in our engineering institute is a specialized workspace where students immerse themselves in the art of fashion design and textile draping. Equipped with design tools, mannequins, and fabrics, it fosters creativity and hands-on learning in fashion-related disciplines. This lab plays a pivotal role in nurturing students\' design skills, preparing them for careers in the fashion and textile industries.</string>
    <string name="ac129">The Apparel Manufacturing Lab in our NITER is a state-of-the-art facility where students gain practical experience in garment production processes. Equipped with modern sewing machines and pattern-making tools, it offers hands-on training in apparel manufacturing techniques. This lab is integral to preparing students for careers in the fashion and apparel industry by honing their skills in clothing production and quality control.</string>
    <string name="ac216">The Medical Center in our Institute is a valuable resource for students and staff, providing access to healthcare services and medical support. Staffed with qualified medical professionals, it offers primary care, consultations, and health-related guidance, ensuring the well-being of our campus community. This center plays a crucial role in promoting the health and welfare of individuals within our educational institution.</string>
    <string name="ac217">This computer lab in our NITER is a high-tech hub where students access cutting-edge technology and software for coursework, research, and projects. With modern workstations and reliable network infrastructure, it offers a conducive environment for coding, simulations, and data analysis. This lab is essential for fostering digital literacy and innovation among our engineering students.</string>
    <string name="ac301">Design Studio Lab for the Fashion Design Department in our engineering institute is a vibrant and specialized workspace where aspiring designers bring their fashion visions to life. With state-of-the-art equipment, sewing machines, and pattern-making tools, it offers a hands-on environment for creativity and garment production. This lab is pivotal in nurturing the skills and expertise required for success in the dynamic and competitive field of fashion design.</string>
    <string name="ac308">The Power Systems and Communication Engineering Lab in our engineering institute, specifically tailored for EEE (Electrical and Electronic Engineering), is an advanced facility where students gain hands-on experience in power system analysis and communication engineering. Equipped with cutting-edge equipment, it offers practical training in designing and optimizing electrical systems and communication networks. This lab is instrumental in preparing students for careers in the fields of electrical engineering and communication technology, emphasizing proficiency in complex electrical systems and modern communication networks.</string>
    <string name="ac131"> Programming Lab in our engineering institute is a space where students learn to code and develop software applications. Equipped with modern computers and software tools, it provides hands-on experience in programming languages and algorithm development. This lab is instrumental in enhancing students\' coding skills and preparing them for the technology-driven demands of the engineering industry.</string>


    <string name="NCC">Click <a href="https://www.facebook.com/groups/NITERComputerClub"> here </a> to open NCC facebook page.</string>
    <string name="NIS">Click <a href="https://www.facebook.com/niterislamicsociety"> here </a> to open NIS facebook page.</string>
    <string name="NFPS">Click <a href="https://www.facebook.com/NITER.Photographic"> here </a> to open NFPS facebook page.</string>
    <string name="NGSC">Click <a href="https://www.facebook.com/Nitergamesandsportsclub"> here </a> to open NGSC facebook page.</string>
    <string name="NDS">Click <a href="https://www.facebook.com/niternds"> here </a> to open NDS facebook page.</string>
    <string name="NCuC">Click <a href="https://www.facebook.com/niterculturalclub"> here </a> to open NCuC facebook page.</string>
    <string name="News">Click <a href="https://www.facebook.com/niter.news"> here </a> to open NITER News facebook page.</string>
    <string name="mastul">Click <a href="https://www.facebook.com/mastul.org"> here </a> to open মাস্তুল facebook page.</string>
    <string name="wing">Click <a href="https://www.facebook.com/groups/3079194312361297"> here </a> to open NITER Wing - Team Matrix facebook page.</string>
    <string name="NSS">Click <a href="https://www.facebook.com/nitersciencesociety"> here </a> to open NSS facebook page.</string>
    <string name="NLC">Click <a href="https://www.facebook.com/NITERLC"> here </a> to open NLC facebook page.</string>
    <string name="NFC">Click <a href="https://www.facebook.com/profile.php?id=100089385592186"> here </a> to open NFC facebook page.</string>
    <string name="NCc">Click <a href="https://www.facebook.com/NITERCareerClub"> here </a> to open NCC facebook page.</string>
    <string name="NBIC">Click <a href="https://www.facebook.com/niterbusinessandinnovationclub"> here </a> to open NBIC facebook page.</string>



    <string name="boys">A well-furnished 3-storied main hostel building and an extension building dedicated for male students with canteen, TV and common room facility. Every room of the hostel has an attached bath, washroom, and a sufficient number of furniture to accommodate students. The canteen, common room, indoor games instruments, natural beauty, sound and attractive atmosphere of the area is very helpful to students for carrying out their study pleasantly. A total number of 400 students can be accommodated in the male hostel.</string>
    <string name="girls">The girls hostel comprises three floors. For second, third, and fourth years, on the first and second floors.For one year, on the third floor. There is a reading room and a common area. It contains an indoor gaming area, two freezers, and one television. Every floor features one kitchen, eight bathrooms on the third floor, twelve bathrooms on the second floor, twelve bathrooms on the first floor, two washing machines, and one water filter on each floor. First floor: 82 seats in total; room 10; second floor: 88 seats in total; room 11; third floor: 1st year student number of seats varies depending on student population.</string>
</resources>